<resources>
    <string name="app_name">GoslingLovelace</string>
    <string name="ada">Between 1842 and 1843, Ada translated an article by Italian military engineer Luigi Menabrea on the calculating engine, supplementing it with an elaborate set of notes, simply called Notes. These notes contain what many consider to be the first computer program—that is, an algorithm designed to be carried out by a machine. Other historians reject this perspective and point out that Babbage\’s personal notes from the years 1836/1837 contain the first programs for the engine.[10] Lovelace\’s notes are important in the early history of computers. She also developed a vision of the capability of computers to go beyond mere calculating or number-crunching, while many others, including Babbage himself, focused only on those capabilities.[11] Her mindset of \”poetical science\” led her to ask questions about the Analytical Engine (as shown in her notes) examining how individuals and society relate to technology as a collaborative tool.[6]
She died of uterine cancer in 1852 at the age of 36.
        On 21 April, Lord Byron signed the deed of separation, although very reluctantly, and left England for good a few days later.[16] Aside from an acrimonious separation, Lady Byron continued throughout her life to make allegations about her husband\’s immoral behaviour.[17] This set of events made Lovelace infamous in Victorian society. She did not have a relationship with her father. He died in 1824 when she was eight years old. Her mother was the only significant parental figure in her life.[18] Lovelace was not shown the family portrait of her father until her 20th birthday.[19]
Lovelace did not have a close relationship with her mother. She was often left in the care of her maternal grandmother Judith, Hon. Lady Milbanke, who doted on her. However, because of societal attitudes of the time—which favoured the husband in any separation, with the welfare of any child acting as mitigation—Lady Byron had to present herself as a loving mother to the rest of society. This included writing anxious letters to Lady Milbanke about her daughter\’s welfare, with a cover note saying to retain the letters in case she had to use them to show maternal concern.[20] In one letter to Lady Milbanke, she referred to her daughter as \”it\”: \”I talk to it for your satisfaction, not my own, and shall be very glad when you have it under your own.\”[21] Lady Byron had her teenage daughter watched by close friends for any sign of moral deviation. Lovelace dubbed these observers the \”Furies\” and later complained they exaggerated and invented stories about her.[22]
</string>
    <string name="james">James Gosling received a Bachelor of Science from the University of Calgary and his M.A. and Ph.D. from Carnegie Mellon University, all in computer science. He wrote a version of Emacs called Gosling Emacs (Gosmacs) while working toward his doctorate. He built a multi-processor version of Unix for a 16-way computer system while at Carnegie Mellon University, before joining Sun Microsystems. He also developed several compilers and mail systems there.
Gosling was with Sun Microsystems between 1984 and 2010 (26 years). He is known as the father of the Java programming language. He got the idea for the Java VM while writing a program to port software from a PERQ by translating Perq Q-Code to VAX assembler and emulating the hardware. He left Sun Microsystems on April 2, 2010 after it was acquired by the Oracle Corporation, citing reductions in pay, status, and decision-making ability, along with change of role and ethical challenges. He has since taken a very critical stance towards Oracle in interviews, noting that \”during the integration meetings between Sun and Oracle, where we were being grilled about the patent situation between Sun and Google, we could see the Oracle lawyer\’s eyes sparkle.\” He clarified his position during the Oracle v Google trial over Android: \”While I have differences with Oracle, in this case, they are on the right. Google totally slimed Sun. We were all really disturbed, even Jonathan Schwartz; he just decided to put on a happy face and tried to turn lemons into lemonade, which annoyed a lot of folks on Sun.\” However, he approved of the court\’s ruling that APIs should not be copyrightable.
In March 2011, Gosling left Oracle to work at Google. Six months later, he followed his colleague Bill Vass and joined a startup called Liquid Robotics. In late 2016, Liquid Robotics was acquired by Boeing. Following the acquisition, Gosling left Liquid Robotics to work at Amazon Web Services as Distinguished Engineer in May 2017.
He is an adviser at the Scala company Lightbend, Independent Director at Jelastic, and Strategic Advisor for Eucalyptus, and is a board member of DIRTT Environmental Solutions.
He is known for his love of proving \”the unknown\” and has noted that his favorite irrational number is √2. He has a framed picture of the first 1,000 digits of √2 in his office.</string>
</resources>
